Guide to the Fred Chappell Papers, 1944-2019 and undated RL.00213
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Printed Material Series, 1955-1997 and undated
  - Poetry Subseries, 1955-1997 and undated
    - 1978
      - Epoch, Vol. XXVII, No. 2, Winter: The Peaceable Kingdom of Emerald Windows (Box PP-1)
    - 1979
      - Bay Leaves, 1978-1979: Stillpoint Hill That Other Shore (Box PP-1)
      - Hard Scuffle, Folio: Dressage (Box PP-1)
      - Epoch, Vol. XXIX, No. 1, Fall: My Grandmother's Dream of Plowing (Box PP-1)
      - International Poetry Review, Celtic Issue, Vol. 5, No. 1, Spring: Second Wind (Box PP-2)
      - The Lyricist, Vol. XIII, Spring: My Grandfather Dishes the Dirt (Box PP-2)
      - Quarterly West, No. 8, Winter: At the Grave of Virgil Campbell (Box PP-2)
    - 1980
      - Colonnades, Vol. 31, Spring: The Intimation (Box PP-2)
      - The Davidson Miscellany, Vol. 16, No. 1, Spring: The Old Actor, and "B" (Box PP-2)
      - The Georgia Review, Vol. XXXIV, No. 1, Spring: Earthsleep (Box PP-2)
      - Willow Springs, No. 6, Spring: Page, Astrologer (Box PP-2)
      - The Hollow Spring Review of Poetry, Vol. III, No. 2: Lady Susan's Morning Dream of the Garden (Box PP-2)
      - Southern Poetry Review, Vol. XX, No. 2, Fall: Forever Mountain (Box PP-2)
      - The Texas Review, Vol. 1, No. 2, Fall: My Father Washes His Hands and Appalachian Apples (Box PP-2)
    - 1981
      - Bay Leaves, No. 16: My Mother Shoots the Breeze (Box PP-2)
      - The Hollow Spring, Vol. IV, No. 1: The Transformed Twilight: A Lieder Cycle (Box PP-2)
      - The Arts Journal, Jan.: An Old Woman Reads Her Bible (Box PP-2)
      - The Arts Journal, Apr.: IV Cleaning the Well, Fast Ball, VI My Grandfather's Church Goes Up, and Third Base Coach (Box PP-2)
      - Southern Poetry Review, Vol. XXI, No. 1, Spring: The Homunculus (Box PP-2)
      - Radford, Vol. 3, No. 1, Fall: The Admiral (Box PP-2)
      - Virginia Quarterly Review, Vol. 57, No. 4, Autumn: Scarecrow Colloquy (Box PP-2)
    - 1982
      - Plainsong Vol. IV, No. 1, Spring: The Lost Carnival (Box PP-2)
      - Light Years 3, July: Afterseasons and Countershades (Box PP-2)
      - Black Willow, Vol. 1, No. 1, Fall: Astrologer (Box PP-2)
      - Southern Poetry Review, Vol. XXIII, No. 2, Fall: Windows and A Prayer for the Mountains (Box PP-2)
    - 1983
      - Abatis Two: Leo Connellan: How the Job Gets Done (Box PP-2)
      - Hemlocks and Balsams, Vol. 5: Digs (Box PP-2)
      - Ploughshares, Vol. 9, Nos. 2 & 3: Urleid (Box PP-2)
      - Poetry, Vol. CXLII, No. 6: Narcissus and Echo and Message (Box PP-2)
      - The Chariton Review, Vol. 9, No. 1, Spring: An Old Mountain Woman Reading the Book of Job (Box PP-2)
      - The Humane Society of Guilford County, Inc. Annual Report, Winter: Horses in a Dark Barn (Box PP-2)
    - 1984
      - The Little Balkans Review, Vol. 4, No. 2, Winter: Tate's Forty Birthdays and Song for Disembodied Voice (Box PP-2)
      - Coraddi, Winter: Slow Harbor (Box PP-2)
      - The Davidson Miscellany, Vol. 19, No. 2, Spring: First Star (Box PP-2)
      - James Dickey Newsletter, Vol. 1, No. 1, Fall: Phaethon (Box PP-2)
      - Southern Humanities Review, Vol. XVIII, No. 4, Fall: Latencies (Box PP-2)
      - Tar River Poetry, Vol. 24, No. 1, Fall: My Hand Placed on a Rubens Drawing (Box PP-2)
    - 1985
      - The Chattahoochee Review, Vol. V, No. 3, Spring: Tolstoy's Bear, Horses in a Dark Barn, and The Writer and the Little Magazine (essay) (Box PP-2)
      - Mossy Creek Journal, No. 9, Spring: Turner Seascape (Box PP-2)
      - The Arts Journal, Vol. 10, No. 7, Apr.: Stoic Poet (Box PP-2)
      - Avenue Liefde, Vol. 20, No. 4, Apr.: De Koningin (Box PP-2)
      - America, Vol. 153, No. 2, July 20-27: Bee and Word (Box PP-2)
    - 1986
      - Hemlocks and Balsams, Vol. 6: Four Poems from Martial, (translation) Grace DiSanto, and Vein of Words ( review) (Box PP-2)
      - Boston Review, Vol. XI, No. 1, Feb.: Spitballer, My Grandmother Washes Her Feet, Humility, Recovery of Sexual Desire After a Bad Cold, The Story, and My Father's Hurricane (Box PP-2)
      - Harper's Magazine, Vol. 272, No. 1632, May: Humility (Box PP-2)
      - The Georgia Review, Vol. XL, No. 2, Summer: A Prologue to the Georgics (Box PP-2)
      - Now and Then, Vol. 3, No. 2, Summer: A Prayer for the Mountains (Box PP-2)
      - Publication of the Society for Literature and Science, Vol. 1, No. 4: Voyagers and Subject Matter (Box PP-2)
      - College English, Vol. 48, No. 5, Sept.: A Glorious Twilight, The Betrayal, and The Embitterment of Charity (Box PP-2)
      - The Amicus Journal, Vol. 8, No. 2, Fall: Tolstoy's Bear (Box PP-2)
      - The Georgia Review, Vol. XL, No. 3, Fall: Earthsleep (Box PP-2)
      - Boulevard: Journal of Contemporary Writing, Vol. 1, No. 1 & 2, Winter: Slow Harbor and Messages (Box PP-2)
    - 1987
      - George Herbert Journal, Vol. 10, No. 1 & 2, Fall 1986/Spring 1987: For Amy Charles (Box PP-3)
      - The Archive, Vol. 99, No. 2: Ideally Grasping the Actual Flower (Box PP-3)
      - Chronicles: A Magazine of American Culture, Vol. 11, No. 4, Apr.: Years Afterward (Box PP-3)
      - Raccoon, 24/25, May: Feast (Box PP-3)
      - Poultry: A Magazine of Voice, Series 2, No. 6, Oct. 30: The Hen's Lament: Ubi Sunt (Box PP-3)
    - 1988
      - Publication of the Society for Literature and Science, Vol. 3, No. 3, May: The Era of Arbitrary Starlight (Box PP-3)
      - Tar River Poetry, Vol. 28, No. 1, Fall: Relativity (Box PP-3)
      - Chronicles: A Magazine of American Culture, Vol. 12, No. 10, Nov.: Some Epigrams: Malgre Lui, Agriculture, Televangelist, and The Epigramatist (Box PP-3)
    - 1989
      - UNCG Alumni News, Vol. 77, No. 3, Summer: The Reader and Bee (Box PP-3)
    - 1990
      - Crypt of Cthulhu, Vol. 9, No. 6: Weird Tales (Box PP-3)
      - The Formalist Vol. 1, Issue 2: Ave atque Vale, Upon a Confessional Poet, and Chronicling the Culture: The Poet and the Modern Epic Ambition (essay) (Box PP-3)
      - Hemlocks and Balsams, Vol. 10: The Reprobate (epitaph), Lydia (epitaph), Stiff, Sex Manual, Upon a Municipal Architect, and A Charm Against the Critic (Box PP-3)
      - Wolfpen Branch: Literature (Box PP-3)
      - The Sow's Ear, Vol. 2, No. 2, Spring: Good Read (Box PP-3)
      - The Chronicles of Higher Education, Mar. 14: The Stories (Box PP-3)
      - Chronicles: A Magazine of American Culture, Vol. 14, No. 9, September: Intellectual Pollution: Some Literary Critics Portrayed (Box PP-3)
      - American Literary Review, Vol. 1, No. 2, Fall: Avignon Suite (Box PP-3)
    - 1991
      - The Snail's Pace Review, Vol. 1, No. 1, Spring: The Small Goodbye (Box PP-3)
      - Eastern Music Festival, June 22-Aug. 3: An Anniversary Toast (Box PP-3)
    - 1992
      - The Oxford American, Spring: The Censor and Televangelist (Box PP-3)
    - 1993
      - The Oxford American, Vol. 3: U.S. Porn Queen (Box PP-3)
      - Tar River Poetry, Vol. 33, No. 1, Fall: The Voices (Box PP-3)
      - The Epigrammatist, Vol. 4, No. 3, Dec.: Televangelist, El Perfecto, and The Epigrammatist (epigrams) (Box PP-3)
    - 1994
      - Southern Humanities Review, Vol. XXVIII, No. 1, Winter: The Rose and Afterward (Box PP-3)
      - The Chattahoochee Review, Vol. XV, No. 1, Fall: Horses in a Dark Barn and Readings (Box PP-3)
      - The Epigrammatist, Vol. 5, No. 3: Essay on Certain Species of Epigram (Box PP-3)
      - Southern Humanities Review, Vol. 28, No. 1, Winter: The Rose and Afterward (Box PP-3)
    - 1995
      - Image, No. 10, Sept.: Epilogue to 'Spring Garden' (Box PP-3)
    - 1996
      - Solo, No. 1, Spring: The Debate and Family Gathering (Box PP-3)
    - 1997
      - Victoria Press, No. 3: On the Wing (Box PP-3)
    - N.d.
      - The Brown Bag, Vol. 1, No. 4: The Mother (Box PP-3)
      - Cream City Review, Vol. 11, No. 1: Meanwhile and Pierrot Escapes (Box PP-3)
      - New CollAge Magazine, Vol. 15, No. 1: Regret (Box PP-3)
      - New CollAge Magazine, Vol. 20, Nos. 1 & 2: Regret (Box PP-3)
  - Essays Subseries, 1969-1996
    Serials containing essays by Chappell, arranged chronologically.
    - 1969 (Box PE-1)
      - The Above Ground Review, Vol. 1, No. 3, Winter: Seven Propositions About Poetry and Personality (Box PE-1)
    - 1970
      - UNCG Alumni News, Vol. 85, No. 3, Spring: The Moon: Why Pay More? (Box PE-1)
    - 1971
      - St. Andrews Review, Vol. 1, No. 3, Fall-Winter: 'I'm in the Racket': Carolyn Kizer's Poetry (Box PE-1)
    - 1975
      - Phoebe: The George Mason Review: Modesty and Honesty: Reactionary Notes on a Folk Phrase (Box PE-1)
      - The Archive, Vol. 81, No. 1, Fall: "The Surface of Earth: A Pavement of Good Intentions" (Box PE-1)
    - 1982
      - American Arts, May: An Absent Middle (Box PE-1)
    - 1984
      - The Mississippi Quarterly, Vol. 37, No. 1, Winter: A Pact with Faustus (Box PE-1)
      - Telescope, Vol. 3, No. 3, Fall: Griffith Still (Box PE-1)
    - 1985
      - The South Atlantic Quarterly, Vol. 84, No. 1, Winter: First Night Once More (Box PE-1)
    - 1987
      - Hemlocks and Balsams, Vol. 7: Skepticism (Box PE-1)
      - The Bookmark, 55: Portrait of the Reader Reading (Box PE-1)
    - 1992
      - Turnstile, Vol. III, No. 2: First Attempts (Box PE-1)
      - ANQ: A Quarterly Journal of Short Articles, Notes, and Reviews, Vol. 5, No. 4, Oct.: The Nineties (Box PE-1)
    - 1993
      - North Carolina Literary Review, Vol. 1, No. 2, Spring: The Curtain Rises (Box PE-1)
    - 1994
      - The Greensboro News and Record, Jan. 30: Imagining Life as a Writer (Box PE-1)
      - Re-Publish, Vol. 1, No. 1, Spring: The Nineties (Box PE-1)
      - Chronicles, Vol. 18, No. 5, May: Writer and Community (Box PE-1)
    - 1996
      - Sewanee Review, Vol. 104, No. 3, Summer: Taking Measure (Box PE-1)
  - Reviews Subseries, 1971-1997
    Serials containing reviews by Chappell, arranged chronologically.
    - 1971 (Box PR-1)
      - Mill Mountain Review, 1971: "The Lion-Tamer: George Garrett's Short Stories" (Box PR-1)
    - 1973
      - The South Atlantic Quarterly, Vol. 72, No. 1, Winter: "Furguson, The Poetry of Randall Jarrell" (Box PR-1)
    - 1975
      - Science-Fiction Studies, Vol. 2, Part 2, July: Menville's Thesis on the SF Film (Box PR-1)
      - The South Atlantic Quarterly, Vol. 74, No. 4, Autumn: "Coles, Irony in the Mind's Life: Essays on Novels by James Agee, Elizabeth Brown, and George Eliot" (Box PR-1)
      - Duke Alumni Register, Oct.: "The Surface of Earth" (Box PR-1)
      - Science-Fiction Studies, Vol. 2, Part 3, Nov.: The SF Film: The Metropolis and Things to Come (Box PR-1)
    - 1976
      - The South Atlantic Quarterly, Vol. 75, No. 2, Spring: W.H. Auden: A Tribute (Box PR-1)
      - Southern Poetry, Vol. 16, No. 1, Spring: Statues of the Grass (Box PR-1)
    - 1978
      - Magazine Litteraire, No. 133, Fevrier: Structure Comique de Le Bruit et la Fureur (Box PR-1)
    - 1979
      - The Arts Journal, Vol. 4, No. 11, Aug.: 'Caesarion' & 'Search Party': Two Really Damn Good Poems (Box PR-1)
    - 1980
      - The Greensboro Sun, Vol. 8, No. 2, May: Candy Flynt - A Physical Excitement Possesses Her (Box PR-1)
      - The Greensboro Sun, Vol. 8, No. 3, June: Casually Grubby in Funk City (Box PR-1)
    - 1981
      - Briarpatch, Vol. 3, No. 1: Revisioning (Box PR-1)
      - December Magazine: R.V. Cassill Issue, Vol. 23, Nos. 1/2: "Clem Anderson, Two Decades" (Box PR-1)
      - The North Carolina Humane Federation, Inc.: News and Views, Vol. 3, No. 1, Mar.: Animal Factories (Box PR-1)
      - The Chariton Review, Vol. 7, No. 2, Fall: Timescape (Box PR-1)
    - 1982
      - Literary Magazine Review, Vol. 1, No. 2, Spring: South Dakota Review (Box PR-1)
      - Appalachian Journal, Vol. 9, No. 4, Summer: The High-Pitched Laugh of a Painted Lady (Box PR-1)
      - The South Atlantic Quarterly, Vol. 81, No. 3, Summer: Double Lyric: Divisiveness and Communal Creativity in Recent English Poetry (Box PR-1)
      - Uwharrie Review, Vol. 7, No. 1, Summer: New Poetry: Bright Books, Two Real Winners (Box PR-1)
      - Northstate Reader, Vol. 2, No. 5, Sept.: The Inarticulate Man: Two Sides of the Woman's Mirror (Box PR-1)
      - The Georgia Review, Vol. 36, No. 3, Fall: "On Robert J. Higg's Laurel and Thorn: The Athlete in American Literature" (Box PR-1)
      - The South Atlantic Quarterly, Vol. 81, No. 4, Autumn: The Lost America of Love: Reading Robert Creeley, Edward Dorn, and Robert Duncan (Box PR-1)
      - The Journal of Popular Film and Television, Vol. IX, No. 4, Winter: The Limits of Infinity, by Sobchak (Box PR-1)
    - 1983
      - Literary Magazine Review, Vol. 1, No. 4, Winter: The Hudson Review (Box PR-1)
      - Southern Humanities Review, Vol. 17, No. 2, Spring: "Cavell's Pursuits of Happiness: The Hollywood Comedy of Remarriage" (Box PR-1)
      - Western Humanities Review, Vol. 37, No. 3, Autumn: Recent Poetry (Box PR-1)
      - The South Atlantic Quarterly, Vol. 82, No. 1, Winter: "Young, Tennessee Writers" (Box PR-1)
    - 1984
      - The Iron Mountain Review: James Still Issue, Vol. 2, No. 1, Summer: 'Menfolks Are Heathens': Cruelty in James Still's Short Stories (Box PR-1)
      - North Carolina Independent, Oct. 11-24: Dirty Little Secrets (Box PR-1)
      - The North Carolina Independent, Vol. 2, No. 22, Nov. 23-Dec. 6: Seek, and Ye Shall Find The Shadow's Source (Box PR-1)
    - 1985
      - Postscript, No. 2: What Did Adrian Leverkuhn Create? (Box PR-1)
      - The Texas Review, Vol. VI and No. 3 and 4, Fall/Winter: "George Garrett's An Evening Performance: New and Selected Short Stories" (Box PR-1)
      - The New York Times Book Review, Oct. 13: Sepia Photographs and Jazz Solos (Box PR-1)
      - DUKE: A Magazine for Alumni and Friends, Vol. 71, No. 4, Mar.-Apr.: Tiger Lilies: An American Childhood (Box PR-1)
    - 1986
      - Hemlocks and Balsams, Vol. 6: Vein of Words (review) and Four Poems from Martial (poem) (Box PR-1)
      - Literary Magazine Review, Vol. 5, No. 1, Spring: Chicago Review (Box PR-1)
      - Parnassus: Poetry in Review, Spring/Summer: Small Change for the Long Haul (Box PR-1)
      - DUKE: A Magazine for Alumni and Friends, July-Aug.: The Accidental Tourist (Box PR-1)
      - James Dickey Newsletter, Vol. 3, No. 1, Fall: "Portrait of the Poet as Teacher: James Dickey by Grace DiSanto" (Box PR-1)
    - 1987
      - Literary Magazine Review, Vol. 5, No. 4, Winter: The Southern Review (Box PR-1)
      - Pembroke Magazine, No. 19: Edward C. Lynskey: Putting Things Simply (Box PR-1)
      - Appalachian Journal, Vol. 14, No. 3, Spring: "O-Zone, by Theroux" (Box PR-1)
      - UNCG Alumni News, Summer: Mother Love: Sisters Grapple with Cobwebs that Mom Left (Box PR-1)
    - 1988
      - Chronicles: A Magazine of American Culture, Vol. 12, No. 4, Apr.: Paz (Box PR-1)
      - Literary Magazine Review, Vol. 7, No. 1, Spring: Editor's Choice II (Box PR-1)
      - The Chattahoochee Review, Vol. 9, No. 1, Fall: 'Stone Axes': Randall Jarrell's Vision of the Poet's Place (Box PR-1)
    - 1989 (Box PR-2)
      - National Review, Vol. 41, No. 3, Feb. 24: A Good Listener in a Talking Country (Box PR-2)
      - Cotton Boll: Atlanta Review, Vol. 4, No. 2, Spring: Out of the Hills of Certainty: Miller Williams' Skeptical Science (Box PR-2)
      - National Review, Vol. 41, No. 5, Mar. 24: American Gothic (Box PR-2)
      - The Georgia Review, Vol. 43, No. 2, Summer: Purple Patches, Fuddle, and the Hard Noon Light (Box PR-2)
      - Chronicles: A Magazine of American Culture, Nov.: Understand Me Completely (Box PR-2)
      - UNCG Alumni News, Vol. 77, No. 2, Winter: Natural Theology (Box PR-2)
    - 1990
      - Chronicles: A Magazine of American Culture, Apr.: Large Canvas, Long Reach (Box PR-2)
      - The Texas Review, Vol. 11, No. 1 and 2, Spring/Summer: Miller's Hard Evidence (Box PR-2)
    - 1991
      - DUKE: A Magazine for Alumni and Friends, Vol. 77, No. 2, Dec. 1990-Jan. 1991: No Guarantees (Box PR-2)
      - Gulf Stream Magazine, No. 4: Plato At Scratch Daniels and Other Stories (Box PR-2)
      - UNCG Alumni News, Vol. 79, No. 4, Summer: Transparent Gestures: A Grand Book (Box PR-2)
      - UNCG Alumni News, Vol. 80, No. 1, Fall: "The Ragged Way People Fall out of Love, by Elizabeth Cox" (Box PR-2)
      - The Georgia Review, Vol. 45, No. 4, Winter: Family Matters (Box PR-2)
      - UNCG Alumni News, Vol. 79, No. 2, Winter: "The Blue Valleys by Robert Morgan" (Box PR-2)
    - 1992
      - Gulf Stream Magazine, No. 6: The Tennessee Waltz (Box PR-2)
      - Literary Magazine Review, Vol. 11, No. 2, Summer: Field (Box PR-2)
      - Louisiana Literature, Vol. 9, No. 2, Fall: The Exiled Heart: A Meditative Autobiography (Box PR-2)
      - The Georgia Review, Vol. 46, No. 4, Winter: Maiden Voyages and Their Pilots (Box PR-2)
    - 1993
      - Mossy Creek Reader, No. 3, Spring: "New Stories by Mildred Haun" (Box PR-2)
      - The Georgia Review, Vol. 47, No. 2, Summer: Figured Carpets: the Collected and the Selected (Box PR-2)
      - Necrofile: The Review of Horror Fiction, Issue 9, Summer: Discontent With the Ordinary State of Things (Box PR-2)
      - Chronicles, Vol. 17, No. 10, Oct.: The Hard to Catch Mercy (Box PR-2)
      - The Georgia Review, Vol. 47, No. 4, Winter: Let Me Count the Ways: Five Love Poets (Box PR-2)
    - 1994
      - The Georgia Review, Vol. 48, No. 2, Summer: Taking Sides: 6 Poetry Anthologies (Box PR-2)
      - Southern Humanities Review, Vol. 28, No. 3, Summer: Casting Sequences and Fanatic Hearts (Box PR-2)
      - The New York Review of Science Fiction, Vol. 6, No. 12, Aug.: Inageh and The Sons of Noah and Other Stories, by Jack Cady (Box PR-2)
      - The Georgia Review, Vol. 48, No. 4, Winter: Wise Saws When Last Seen (Box PR-2)
    - 1995
      - International Poetry Review, Vol. 21, No. 1, Spring: Montale's Reactionary Revolution (Box PR-2)
      - Now and Then: The Appalachian Magazine, Vol. 12, No. 1, Spring: Lost and Found (Box PR-2)
      - The Georgia Review, Vol. 49, No. 3, Fall: A Million Million Suns: Poetry and Science (Box PR-2)
      - The World and I, Dec.: Soulful Grotesques (Box PR-2)
    - 1996
      - The Oxford American, Spring: Salvation in Order (Box PR-2)
      - The Georgia Review, Vol. 50, No. 1, Spring: Five New Southern Women Poets (Box PR-2)
      - Packrat #13, Apr.: Looking Backward: Astounding Stories - Sept., 1935 (Box PR-2)
      - Necrofile: The Review of Horror Fiction, No. 21, Summer: Doubly Spooked (Box PR-2)
      - Now and Then: The Appalachian Magazine, Vol. 13, No. 2, Summer: Counting the Sums (Box PR-2)
      - The Georgia Review, Vol. 50, No. 3, Fall: Piecework: the Longer Poem Returns (Box PR-2)
    - 1997
      - The World and I, Feb., 1997: In the Company of Immortals (Box PR-2)
      - The Georgia Review, Vol. 51, No. 1, Spring, 1997: The Contemporary Long Poem: Minding the Kinds (Box PR-2)
  - Miscellaneous Subseries, 1956-1997 and undated
    Serials containing miscellaneous writings by Chappell such as introductions and forewords, translations, interviews with him, and reviews of his works. Serials with which he has some affiliation such as serving on editorial or advisory boards or serving as a contest judge are also included here. Arranged in chronological order. Publishers' and dealers' catalogs with announcements about his works are at the end of the subseries.
    - 1955 (Box PM-1)
      - The Archive, Vol. 68, No. 2, Dec.: 2 Forms of Animal Faith (vignettes--see Printed Material: Poetry Subseries, same date) (Box PM-1)
    - 1956
      - Archive, Vol. 68, No. 4, Apr.: Poetry Editor (Box PM-1)
    - 1963
      - The Archive, Vol. 75, No. 1, Nov.: review of Chappell's It Is Time, Lord, by Alex Raybin (Box PM-1)
    - 1966
      - The Greensboro Review, Vol. II, No. 1, Dec.: Advisory Editor (Box PM-1)
    - 1972
      - The Furman Magazine, Vol. 19, No. 3, Spring: mentioned in William Blackburn: Teacher of Writers (Box PM-1)
    - 1976
      - International Poetry Review, Vol. II, No. 2, Fall: poetry translations of Vittorio Tommasini (Box PM-1)
    - 1977
      - New River Review, Vol. 2, No. 1: interview with Philip Pierson (Box PM-1)
    - 1978
      - The Mississippi Quarterly, Vol. XXXI, No. 4, Fall: William Blackburn and His Pupils: A Conversation, by James L. W. West, III (offprint, inscribed by West to Chappell) (Box PM-1)
    - 1979
      - Appalachian Writers, July-Oct.: viewer's guide to seven-part interview series produced at WSJK-TV in Knoxville (Box PM-1)
    - 1980
      - The Student, Spring: Is Regional Writing Dead? (Box PM-1)
      - Epoch, Winter: Statement in A Symposium on the Theory and Practice of the Line (Box PM-1)
    - 1981
      - Alumni News: UNC-G, Fall: "The Writing Program" (Box PM-1)
      - Appalachian Journal, Vol. 9, No. 1, Fall: "The Large Vision: Fred Chappell's Midquest," by Rodney Jones (Box PM-1)
    - 1982
      - International Poetry Review, Vol. III, No. 2, Fall: judge, poetry contest (Box PM-1)
    - 1983
      - Telescope V & VI, Spring: survey reply, Sightings on Freud (Box PM-1)
      - Crucible, Spring: N.C.W.C. Lecture (Box PM-1)
      - Appalachian Heritage, Spring: Advisory/Contributing Editor (Box PM-1)
      - The Texas Review, Vol. IV, nos. 1& 2, Spring/Summer: Guest Fiction Editor (Box PM-1)
      - Appalachian Heritage, Summer: Advisory/Contributing Editor (Box PM-1)
      - The Texas Review, Vol. IV, nos. 3 & 4, Fall/Winter: Guest Fiction Editor (Box PM-1)
      - Postscript: listed in Program Schedule (Box PM-1)
    - 1984
      - Mississippi Quarterly, Vol. XXXVII, No. 1, Winter: Special Fred Chappell Issue (Box PM-1)
      - Pembroke Magazine, 16: inscribed "To Susan" (Box PM-1)
      - South Atlantic Review, Vol. 49, No. 3, Sept.: Convention Program (Box PM-1)
    - 1985
      - Circa, Vol. 5, No. 2, Spring: interview by Alex Albright (Box PM-1)
      - The Iron Mountain Review, Vol. II, No. 2, Spring: The Way It Is, Interview by Shelby Stephenson (Box PM-1)
      - Quarterly West, Spring/Summer: Apology for Choosing Two Fine Novellas (judge in contest) (Box PM-1)
      - G: Golden Triad, Vol. 8, No. 4, Fall: interview by Carol Kline (Box PM-1)
      - Coraddi, Winter: Interview by Ian McDowell (Box PM-1)
    - 1986
      - Abatis, Three: Duane Locke: The Clarity of High Walls (Box PM-1)
    - 1987
      - Carolina Quarterly, Vol. 4, No. 3, Spring: Guest Fiction Editor (Box PM-1)
      - American Poetry: Fifth Anniversary Issue, Fall: Reading Jeffers (Box PM-1)
      - Michigan Quarterly Review, Fall: Response to a Question (Box PM-1)
      - Rebel '87, Vol. 29: Fred Chappell: A N.C. Poet (interview) (Box PM-1)
    - 1988
      - Alumni News: UNC-G, Vol. 76, No. 2, Spring: review of Eve Shelnutt's The Musician (Box PM-1)
      - The Iron Mountain Review, Vol. IV, No. 2, Spring: quoted in Pro Tempore (Box PM-1)
      - The Jamais Vu Papers, Vol. 1, No. 8, Apr.: interview (Box PM-1)
      - The National Book Critics Circle Journal, Vol. 14, No. 3, Apr. 1: Letter to Editor (Box PM-1)
      - Ploughshares, Vol. 14, No. 2 & 3: Cathy Carr (a biographical sketch) (Box PM-1)
      - Crypt of Cthulhu, Vol. 7, No. 5, Eastertide: letter to Editor (Box PM-1)
    - 1989 (Box PM-2)
      - The Arts Journal, Vol. 14, No. 8, May: A Man of Letters in the Modern World (Interview) (Box PM-2)
      - The Iron Mountain Review, Vol. 5, No. 1, Spring: For Wilma (Box PM-2)
      - Chronicles: A Magazine of American Culture, July: A Cultural Cincinnatus, by David R. Slavitt (review of Chappell's First and Last Words) (Box PM-2)
      - The Sow's Ear, Vol. 1, No. 4, Fall: Two Poetry Translations (Box PM-2)
      - Chronicles: A Magazine of American Culture, Oct.: advertisement on inside cover (Box PM-2)
      - Deathrealm, Issue 10, Fall/Winter: mentioned in letter to editor (Box PM-2)
      - Chattahoochee Review, Vol. 9, No. 2, Winter: interview by Tim Tarkington (Box PM-2)